hey all welcome back to another
interesting lesson in this Tosca
playlist today we are going to talk
about how we can record executions in
placenta
and this feature was recently introduced
uh at least in the latest versions of
Tosca uh where you can record the
complete execution whenever you run your
test either from scratchbook or from an
execution list
so this particular feature is very
interesting and useful because when
whenever we are executing our automation
test cases from Tosca sometimes it may
happen that uh you you are executing
them uh somewhere on the remote machine
or you are doing distributed execution
right in this cases you may not be
monitoring your executions continuously
and if it is a long test case which
maybe takes a hour or a half an hour
then uh there might be some issue which
pops up in between which breaks your
test and then it is difficult to debug
uh that particular issue because you
have to get and go through your test
case your test steps your modules and
find out where exactly it uh it was
broken even though it will show it in
the logs you can find the errors which
are happening but the error locks are
not really conclusive all the time so
it's really useful if you can take some
screenshot of either the where the issue
happened or you can even have a
recording if your test case fails okay
and then you can look at that recording
and find out where exactly your test
case is failing and then you can go
ahead and easily fix it right
so it's a useful feature but then it has
its own downsides where you have to
store this recordings and then you have
to decide how you can manage this
recordings because this can take up
quite uh some space if you record your
test executions right but there are ways
to manage that but first let's see how
you can use this particular feature okay
now as I said if this feature is not
available in your Tosca Commander it is
because uh you may be using a older
version of Tosca Commander this is
mostly uh available after 15.1 as I know
So currently I am using the 16 person
and I would recommend you to upgrade
your Tosca Commander if you have not
done so okay
so to enable this feature uh we have to
enable something on the settings so when
we go into project and settings
this is where we have to change this
setting and you have to go to a t-box
and under t-box you will find execution
recorder
okay
Now by default this execution recorder
enable execution recorder is disabled
and I can enable it but there are two
more options right so either I can
enable it for all my test executions or
I can only enable it only when my test
case fails which is quite logical also
because I would be more interested when
uh my test case fails I would like to
look at that recording but if you have
got lots of memory and space then you
can even enable it for all the
executions okay
but just for this session
um I will just keep it to enabled okay
uh the output file name template you can
always change it based on how you want
uh it to be
stored okay so it is basically stored
with test case name and execution start
time
uh in the MP4 format but you can change
the name um As You Wish okay
then the output path is under your Tosca
projects okay and there there is a
folder called recordings
uh you can also adjust this output path
if you need to okay so once you enable
this uh you can close the setting and
now whatever executions I do either in
scratchbook or on the execution list my
uh execution recording should be
available on that particular path okay
so for example this last case which we
developed uh for fire event if I go
ahead and run this now
so this particular execution will be
recorded and the mp4 file will be
available on that particular path after
the execution is completed
so do remember that even if you pause uh
the execution your recording won't be
paused okay so it will continue
and once this is completed then um I can
go to that path so you can see here uh
this particular path
it is under C Tosca projects this is the
default path uh if you have not changed
it so then I Tosca Commander under this
we have the recordings folder and inside
this you will see that uh this
particular file has just been created
okay so it's basically a simple
recording of my complete execution
starting from opening the page and
executing that particular test so
whatever you are doing execution it will
basically record the whole screen
okay
so uh that's how you can create a
recording and you can view it
um either based on failures or basically
do it for all your executions
but what if you don't want to run any
particular test case okay or you don't
want to record the execution of
particular test cases because you know
that this may pass all the time so if
you have enabled it for all the test
cases and you still want to filter out
some of the test cases you don't want
because maybe it is too lengthy it will
create a long video or any reason okay
you can do that easily so what you need
to do is either on the folder level or
test case level go ahead and create a
test configuration parameter okay
so here if I go ahead and create a test
configuration parameter and then I just
have to name it avoid
execution
recorder okay so this is the test
configuration parameter name and then
the value should be set to True okay so
you can also have this test
configuration parameter at a root level
and then or at a folder level or at a
test case level okay so you can just set
it to true or false and based on that
you don't even need to change the
setting all the time uh based on this
test configuration parameter it can
figure out uh which test case execution
should be recorded and which should not
be okay
now um if I go ahead and run this this
time around you will see that uh there
would be no execution recording which
will be available
okay before that I should have opened
the pages otherwise this is going to
fail
so let me close this
because I haven't opened the URLs on
this particular test case so this is
always going to fail so let me go ahead
and open this website where we are using
or testing this particular feature
okay so these are multiple tabs which
are open
and I'm going to now run this let's see
okay so if you have not watched this
video already it is present how you can
handle multiple tabs using a constraint
parameter okay which you can add for
your page then based on that it can pick
up any particular tab
okay so uh the execution is completed as
you can see uh it has passed and now if
I go back to my recordings
and I refresh the speech you will see
that no execution recording has been
created okay
so this is a way to filter out uh some
test cases where you don't want any
recordings okay
now uh interestingly as I said you can
use this recording feature both on the
scratchbook also on the execution list
level so let's see
um how this will happen at an execution
list level okay so if I go ahead and
create execution list and then we try to
run this
okay
so let me do this and
I will call it
um
obstacle
Edition okay
and let's go ahead and run this now
uh it's basically the same thing but
this time around uh you can see that
recording as part of your execution list
okay
so let's
wait for this to complete and then this
particular recording will be available
on that particular folder okay
so this is completed now I can and you
can see that uh it has created this
okay so it has named it as per the
execution list test case and there are
two recordings right now one is
scratchbook one is execution list
so this is how you can create execution
recordings uh both from scratchbook also
from the execution list
and it's an useful feature as I said but
uh also it takes up your hard disk space
so use it wisely
and that's all for this particular video
I hope it was interesting uh and useful
so do tune into our channel to watch
more such videos which are coming up
pretty soon so I would suggest you
subscribe to our channel so that you get
notified about all these videos if you
want to learn Tosca right from scratch
so see you again uh with another
interesting feature coming up pretty
soon